What did the Greek-American, former
CIA official say about a possible military
conflict between Greece, Turkey and the USA?
The
former Greek-American CIA expert has therefore given a new dimension to the scenario of a Greek-Turkish war.
Former CIA official John Kyriakou
spoke to Zungla.gr
and journalist Christos Mazanis about
Greece, relations with Turkey,
the US, and global
dangers.  There, in response to a journalist's question
about the scenario of a
possible Greek-Turkish war and the
US stance, he made a truly
bombshell statement.  He said that the
White House, whoever is in
it, will play the role of referee with a
50-50 stance towards both sides.  And
Greece certainly doesn't want that.
He also believes that Turkish
threats to occupy the islands are
unproven by the US and
the international community, but there will always be a
catch.  As we see in the
Cyprus issue, the occupied territories are
not returned through diplomatic
efforts, but only through war or,
better yet, the Lance, as
many report.  According to
the Greek-American expert, Greece will have the
help of the European Union,
Italy, Germany and possibly
Britain in this scenario.  This is
help that certainly won't
give us much.  Certainly because of the
openness of all these countries to
Turkey and the current
Erdogan regime.  Kyriakou, due to his experience as a member of the
Synia and his contacts with
senior intelligence officials
worldwide, spoke openly about the
possibility of a heated episode between
Greece and Turkey.  He
specifically stated that we cannot
trust the US to stand by
Greece.  However, he stressed
that Greece has strong support from
NATO, especially from Italy, France,
Germany and Britain.  He believes
that even without direct
American support, Greece could
cope with Turkey,
as the Turks cannot simply
occupy territories or islands, which is not
acceptable.  When asked about the difference between the
new intelligence officers
compared to his time, Kyriakou
pointed out two key points.  First,
technology has made
espionage operations more difficult, and second, the
role of technology should not
replace human judgment.  This
was the video.  If you liked it, you can
subscribe to the channel to
receive notifications for every new post.  Don't forget
to leave us comments with
your opinion.